

Scott Walsh

Web Developer and UX Designer

Telephone 705-760-2645

Email scmwalsh@gmail.com

Website www.scottwalsh.ca

Located Toronto, ON

Profile

Creating, learning and exploring are my passions. I am an ambitious self-starter with an open-minded attitude which has led me on amazing adventures such as travelling the world and founding my own business. I meet challenges head-on with an approach that demonstrates my ability to exercise creativity when solving problems. I thrive at the intersection where I am able to utilize both my engineering background and creative skills. Full stack web development and UX design allows me to demonstrate my ability to build and problem solve while catering a seamless experience for the end user.

Technical Skills

Ruby on Rails	••••
HTML	• • • • •
CSS	• • • • •
Javascript	••••
Jquery	••••
GIT	• • • • •
Adobe	• • • • •

Experience

Full Stack Developer, Active8 https://activate-app.herokuapp.com/

2015 - Present

- A real time activity based web and mobile responsive application that connects people based on activities near them
- Responsible for creating UX design, mockups and user stories.
 Incorporated Google API and Geocoder to display activities in realtime and worked with team to build the entire front and backend
- Built in Rails and styled with SASS and CSS, our team successfully built and deployed our application in 3 weeks

Owner, Scott Walsh Photography www.scottwwalshphotography.com

2012 - Present

Successfully established, own and manage a freelance photography business for +4 years, acquiring a diverse range of commercial clients

HIGHLIGHTS

Coors Social Media Product/Lifestyle Photographer Rethink Communications. Toronto

- Responsible for shooting and editing all photos for Rethink's client,
 Molson Coors, for the Coors Altitude social media channels
- Strategize with the Rethink account team on monthly client briefs in order to establish creative content for the Coors social calendars

Creative Lead & Social Media Manager Ichiup Beverage Co., Toronto

- Responsible for the planning and execution of all social content for Ichiup's Canadian water brand launch, resulting in the Instagram page growing to +1200 fans
- Worked with the leadership team to create the brand's visual identity,
 shooting +600 photos used in social and print media

Senior Sales Associate Chrysler Jeep Dodge

2012 - 2015

High performing member of the Ontario sales team, receiving awards for delivering sales results and exceeding customer expectations. Proven expert at relationship building and new business development

Education

Web Development, Bitmaker	Labs	2015
TORONTO, ON		

UX Design, Bitmaker Labs	2015 - 2016
TORONTO, ON	

Electrical Engineering, Sir Sanford Fleming 2009 - 2011 PETERBOROUGH, ON

